for 10 years has had zero downtime. This is better than Google, this is better than Amazon,
10 年来一直实现零停机。这比谷歌好，这比亚马逊好，
this is better than Azure. And government and institutions really recognize that, that
这比 Azure 更好。政府和机构确实认识到，
resilience, that battle-testedness. And having been around for so long, there's almost this
韧性，即经过战斗考验的能力。已经存在这么久了，几乎就是这样
concept of lindiness. It's gone through enough that it's trusted. And people care about trust.
林德的概念。它已经经历了足够多的事情，值得信任。人们关心信任。
People care about risk minimization. And there is no better network and there's no better
人们关心风险最小化。没有更好的网络，也没有更好的
ecosystem than Ethereum for doing this. And it's like very obvious. It's often the reason
生态系统比以太坊更适合这样做。这非常明显。往往是这个原因
why it's the number one place to go. This is actually a good setup for my question for
为什么它是排名第一的地方。这实际上是我的问题的一个很好的设置
Samuel, actually. Because what Mo has spoken about is how battle-tested Ethereum is. And so,
事实上，塞缪尔。因为Mo所说的是以太坊是如何久经考验的。所以，
Samuel, you work for Lido, right? It's one of the largest, most battle-tested staking providers in
塞缪尔，你在丽都工作，对吗？它是全球最大、最久经考验的质押提供商之一
the space. And since today I'm trying to be a bit more controversial, I'm going to just go straight
的空间。既然今天我想变得更有争议性，我就直接说吧
to it. Lido is the largest staking provider in all of Ethereum. And some people have kind of
到它。 Lido 是整个以太坊最大的质押提供商。有些人有一种
criticized it as a centralization vector. However, Lido has taken a lot of efforts to help to
批评它是中心化的载体。然而，丽都已经做出了很多努力来帮助
decentralize its validator set. I mean, you've been also doing some of the work with community
分散其验证器集。我的意思是，你也一直在与社区一起做一些工作
staking. So I'm curious, and I'm sure the audience is also curious, how meaningful is this
质押。所以我很好奇，相信观众也很好奇，这有什么意义
decentralization aspect of the Lido staking set? And why, and is it effective in practice?
Lido 质押集的去中心化方面？为什么，它在实践中是否有效？
Yeah, I guess it's true that Lido is the largest liquid staking protocol by TVL. And it's also the
是的，我想 Lido 确实是 TVL 最大的液体质押协议。而且这也是
largest DeFi protocol today at 21 to 22 billion USD. Lido's liquid staking token, SDEath, also
当今最大的 DeFi 协议，价值 21 至 220 亿美元。 Lido 的流动质押代币 SDEath 也
serves as a foundation for many of the leading DeFi use cases today, you know, in the likes of
您知道，它是当今许多领先的 DeFi 使用案例的基础，例如
Pendle, Athena, Aave, Spark, Morpho, Fluid, you know, all these on-chain borrowing and lending
Pendle、Athena、Aave、Spark、Morpho、Fluid，你知道，所有这些链上借贷
protocols is also being used as collateral by, you know, asset managers, fund managers, hedge
你知道，协议也被资产经理、基金经理、对冲基金用作抵押品
funds, on centralized exchanges, on even decentralized venues as well. And to address the,
资金，在中心化交易所，甚至在去中心化场所。为了解决这个问题，
maybe the implied, you know, systemic risk concern here, right, is that there are at least four ways
也许这里隐含的系统性风险担忧是至少有四种方法
that Lido is addressing this. Number one, decentralization. Number two, security. Number
Lido 正在解决这个问题。第一，权力下放。第二，安全。数字
three, transparency. And number four, an ever-improving protocol design. So Lido is
三、透明度。第四，不断改进的协议设计。所以丽都是
not a single entity controlling all of the stake, you know. Lido as a protocol does not run any node
你知道，没有一个实体控制所有股份。 Lido 作为协议不运行任何节点
infrastructure or validated infrastructure by itself. There are more than 700 independent node
基础设施或经过验证的基础设施本身。有700多个独立节点
operators serving the TVL of the Lido protocol. So no single node operator has been programmatically
为 Lido 协议的 TVL 提供服务的运营商。所以没有以编程方式进行单节点操作
delegated more than 1% of the total StakeEath market share. So that reduces or mitigates the
委托占 StakeEath 市场份额 1% 以上。这样就减少或减轻了
correlation risk very significantly by itself. Decentralization also happens on the DAO level,
相关风险本身就非常显着。去中心化也发生在 DAO 层面，
the protocol level, or the governance level. So Lido is one of the only fully on-chain
协议级别或治理级别。所以 Lido 是唯一完全链上的之一
DAOs in the space where the voting outcomes are automatically implemented. You don't need a
自动执行投票结果的 DAO。你不需要一个
separate team of like, you know, small 5% council to actually implement the results of the governance
由 5% 的小型委员会组成的独立团队来实际实施治理结果
voters. On top of that, Lido has pioneered this thing called the dual governance framework,
选民。最重要的是，Lido 开创了双重治理框架的先河，
where not only the governance token holders are able to vote on protocol upgrades,
不仅治理代币持有者能够对协议升级进行投票，
as the ETH holders, or the users of the protocol, are also able to delay the implementation of any
因为 ETH 持有者或协议的用户也可以延迟任何协议的实施
contentious protocol upgrades or DAO proposals until they have had time to exit the protocol.
有争议的协议升级或 DAO 提案，直到他们有时间退出协议。
So that's on the decentralization efforts part. In terms of security, the protocol has invested,
这就是权力下放工作的一部分。在安全性方面，协议投入了，
I think, more than 4 million US dollars over the past five years into security efforts,
我认为，过去五年投入安全工作超过400万美元，
audit reports, security research, bounty programs, etc. There's more than 70 audit
审计报告、安全研究、赏金计划等。有超过 70 项审计
reports produced. The protocol is also fully open source, so it benefits from the global
产生的报告。该协议也是完全开源的，因此受益于全球
mindshell of developers looking at the protocol every day. What's the third item? Transparency,
每天查看协议的开发人员的心态。第三项是什么？透明度，
yes. So the Lido protocol voluntarily reports a lot on the protocol performance, on the performance
是的。所以Lido协议自愿报告了很多关于协议性能，关于性能
of its node operator set, on the protocol health, even like postmortems on security incidents. So
其节点运营商集、协议健康状况，甚至是安全事件的事后分析。所以
it is one of the most transparent and data-rich DAOs you can find out there.
它是您可以找到的最透明、数据最丰富的 DAO 之一。
And last but not least, an ever-improving protocol design. QZ, you mentioned there are new modules
最后但并非最不重要的一点是不断改进的协议设计。 QZ，你提到有新模块
launched on the Lido protocol since the start of the protocol in 2020. So today there are three
自 2020 年协议启动以来，在 Lido 协议上推出。所以今天有 3 个
modules. Number one is the curated set, number two is the simple dbt module, and number three
模块。第一是精选集，第二是简单的 dbt 模块，第三是
the community staking module, all of which adds up to more than 700 independent node operators.
社区质押模块，总共有700多个独立节点运营商。
So Lido also pioneered the adoption of distributed validator technologies, which
因此，Lido 还率先采用了分布式验证器技术，该技术
improves redundancy for and liveness for the Ethereum validator set, and also improves the
提高了以太坊验证器集的冗余性和活跃性，并且还提高了
decentralization. So that's a lot of work for liquid staking. Yeah, and I would also challenge
权力下放。因此，流动性质押的工作量很大。是的，我也想挑战
the notion a little bit. It kind of implies that institutions would de facto try to use Lido
的概念一点点。这有点暗示机构实际上会尝试使用丽都
when they first explore the space, but actually it's not true because they will have to explore
当他们第一次探索太空时，但实际上这不是真的，因为他们必须探索
native staking first. And they will, to what Serena mentioned, they want a familiar legal
首先是原生质押。他们会，正如瑟琳娜提到的，他们想要一个熟悉的法律
structure to interact with for a start, and they need some way to outsource the legal liability.
首先，他们需要某种方式来外包法律责任。
So in essence, they need a traditional service contract when they first start exploring the
所以本质上，当他们第一次开始探索时，他们需要一个传统的服务合同
space, and then slowly they'll move to liquid staking. Right, so I'm also genuinely curious,
空间，然后慢慢地他们会转向流动性质押。对啊，所以我也真的很好奇，
like that sounds like a lot of work to come on board. Why? Are institutions interested in
听起来好像有很多工作要做。为什么？机构是否有兴趣
DeFi so much? Right, why do they even want to do this? Yes. Yeah, so obviously DeFi brings a lot
DeFi 这么多？对啊，他们为什么要这么做呢？是的。是的，显然 DeFi 带来了很多
of cost efficiencies to their cost structure, right? It also brings a lot of new opportunities,
成本效率对其成本结构的影响，对吗？也带来了很多新的机遇，
new business cases for their businesses, right? So it's both a cost-saving endeavor and a revenue
他们的企业有新的商业案例，对吧？因此，这既是一项节省成本的努力，也是一项收入
increasing endeavor. Yeah, I guess what institutions would look for when they explore liquid staking
不断加大努力力度。是的，我猜机构在探索流动性质押时会寻找什么
is twofold. Maybe I condense it to one sentence first. It's the optionality that comes with
是双重的。也许我先把它压缩成一句话。这是随之而来的选择性
liquidity. So this optionality manifests itself in two layers. Number one, they are able to
流动性。因此，这种选择性体现在两个层面上。第一，他们能够
offer rapid withdrawals to their users, for example, or to their own entities. Number two
例如，向用户或其自己的实体提供快速提款。第二
is the opportunity to enhance their rewards through the Ethereum DeFi ecosystem. Yeah,
是通过以太坊 DeFi 生态系统提高奖励的机会。是的，
and that can only happen when you have a liquidity layer on top of native staking,
只有当你在原生质押之上拥有流动性层时，这种情况才会发生，
which is liquid staking. Yeah, so eventually they will want to explore liquid staking,
这就是流动性质押。是的，所以最终他们会想要探索流动性质押，
but they will need to work with the regulators to get there. Do you have a QSC for your entity
但他们需要与监管机构合作才能实现这一目标。您的实体有 QSC
customer? For example, you attract the liquidity on LIDL? Yeah, so LIDL by itself is a permissionless
顾客？例如，您吸引了 LIDL 上的流动性？是的，所以 LIDL 本身就是一个无需许可的
protocol, so anyone anywhere can use it, right? The KYC component, it should be left to the
协议，所以任何地方的任何人都可以使用它，对吗？ KYC 部分，应该留给
institutions who are building on top of the LIDL protocol. Okay, thank you. So this is great because
在 LIDL 协议之上构建的机构。好的，谢谢。所以这很棒因为
you mentioned that point, right? Because I want to talk a bit more about hash keychain.
你提到了这一点，对吗？因为我想多谈谈哈希钥匙串。
I mean, now that you've built the infrastructure and both of you have kind of touched base about
我的意思是，既然你们已经建立了基础设施，而且你们俩都已经了解了一些基础知识
the need for compliance and security, what are some of the most high in-demand applications that you
对合规性和安全性的需求，您最需要的应用程序有哪些
think should be built or your clients or your partners are demanding looking for?
认为应该建立或者您的客户或您的合作伙伴正在要求寻找？
Let me think about it. Do you want to know our new trend of the compliance product or
让我考虑一下。您想了解我们合规产品的新动向还是
what kind of point? Or maybe I hear people are interested in agentic payments? Agent payments?
什么样的点？或者也许我听说人们对代理付款感兴趣？代理付款？
Yeah, well we got a RWA session, for example, the tokenization.
是的，我们有一个 RWA 会话，例如标记化。
And we participate in the Google payment. And we also have our own HSP payment protocol,
并且我们参与Google支付。而且我们也有自己的HSP支付协议，
and it's the base technology for the agent payment in the future.
是未来代理支付的基础技术。
That sounds pretty exciting. Yeah. So just to get you right, I think
听起来很令人兴奋。是的。所以我想只是为了让你正确
hash key, when you launch a new chain, it kind of
哈希键，当你启动一个新链时，它有点像
threads the line between strict institutional compliance and innovation.
划清了严格的制度合规与创新之间的界限。
Yeah, it's a fine line, but there are something to do. For example, we're going to launch
是的，这是一条很好的路线，但还有一些事情要做。例如，我们要推出
a native DAX of our hash keychain named HSKSwap. And the main feature for it is we will launch some
我们的哈希钥匙串的本机 DAX 名为 HSKSwap。它的主要特点是我们将推出一些
RWA assets. And we will launch some pool, like stocks. And we're going to launch new features.
RWA 资产。我们将推出一些资金池，例如股票。我们将推出新功能。
We will put some stocks like SpaceX, like pre-IPO on it. And we cooperate with a
我们将放一些像 SpaceX 这样的股票，比如 IPO 前的股票。我们与一家合作
licensed custodian store, Hybrid Trade. He will integrate their API on our HSKSwap.
许可托管商店，混合贸易。他将把他们的 API 集成到我们的 HSKWap 上。
When the industry comes to today, if we only focus on the native DeFi, maybe
当行业发展到今天，如果我们只关注原生的 DeFi，也许
we will have a little bit of a limitation on it. So we want to put a lot of effort on the stocks.
我们对此会有一点限制。所以我们想在股票上投入很多精力。
First, maybe the American stocks. And the next, maybe we want to explore some other
首先，也许是美国股票。接下来，也许我们想探索一些其他的
region's stocks. Yeah. That sounds actually pretty exciting to be able to get into SpaceX.
地区的股票。是的。能够进入 SpaceX 听起来确实非常令人兴奋。
So my next question is actually for Mo. And I think we've kind of seen a bit of a
所以我的下一个问题实际上是问莫的。我认为我们已经看到了一些
conversation about institutions and what Ethereum can provide. And you mentioned about Lindy.
关于机构和以太坊可以提供什么的对话。你提到了林迪。
From an educational perspective, once again, how do you think we can better communicate what
从教育的角度，你认为我们如何才能更好地传达什么？
Ethereum can afford and what institutions are looking for? Because you can start to see there's
以太坊可以负担得起，哪些机构正在寻找？因为你可以开始看到有
a parallel here. Yeah, I think that's a fantastic question. I think one thing that is extremely
这里有一个平行的。是的，我认为这是一个很棒的问题。我认为有一件事是非常
important and we're already starting to do, I think we should continue doing is help define
重要的是我们已经开始做，我认为我们应该继续做的是帮助定义
what types of adoption we think are important. The type of adoption that strengthens the core
我们认为哪些类型的采用是重要的。加强核心的采用类型
properties that we value in Ethereum. And if we don't do that, then that gets done for us.
我们在以太坊中看重的属性。如果我们不这样做，那么这件事就会为我们完成。
And I think we're starting to do that more and more. Now, I will say that that doesn't come
我认为我们开始越来越多地这样做。现在，我要说的是，那不会发生
in conflict with what institutions want to do. It turns out that institutions actually really
与机构想要做的事情相冲突。事实证明，机构实际上真的
do care about censorship resistance because they want to be able to do transactions without some
确实关心审查阻力，因为他们希望能够在没有某些信息的情况下进行交易
other organization censoring them. They really do care about open source because they don't want
其他组织对其进行审查。他们确实关心开源，因为他们不想要
to be locked into a vendor that they can't basically move away from. They actually really
被锁定到他们基本上无法摆脱的供应商。他们其实真的
do care about privacy and they most definitely care about security. So oftentimes when people
他们确实关心隐私，而且他们绝对关心安全。所以很多时候当人们
talk about these properties, they're like, oh, they come in conflict, but they don't.
谈论这些属性，它们就像，哦，它们发生冲突，但它们并不冲突。
I think if we marry those two, tell people about what kinds of properties are important and why
我想如果我们把这两个人结婚，告诉人们什么样的财产是重要的以及为什么
in a way that they understand is extremely important. And I think they are actually
以他们理解的方式极其重要。我认为他们实际上是
conducive. The second is actually being also transparent about what doesn't work.
有利于。第二个实际上是对无效的内容保持透明。
We were talking about earlier how the wallet infrastructure, the custody infrastructure,
我们之前讨论过钱包基础设施、托管基础设施、
that stuff actually needs a lot of work. And if we can do that, I think that will help basically
那东西实际上需要很多工作。如果我们能做到这一点，我认为这基本上会有帮助
bring to light the areas that we can invest in some more. Those are the things that I think
揭示我们可以进一步投资的领域。这些就是我的想法
are really important that we should highlight more. And in terms of the adoption piece,
确实很重要，我们应该更多地强调。就收养而言，
why do institutions care about a lot of this stuff? Blockchains have been amazing for a couple
为什么机构如此关心这些东西？区块链对于一些人来说是令人惊奇的
of reasons. One is that they're open and inherently we've been building an adversarial environment,
的原因。一是它们是开放的，我们本质上一直在构建一个对抗性环境，
which means they're the most resilient, they're the most safe. And the opportunity with Ethereum
这意味着它们是最有弹性的，也是最安全的。以及以太坊的机会
in general is that it opens up new markets, like Stablecoin is an example of this. It's going to
总的来说，它开辟了新的市场，稳定币就是一个例子。它将
hear $400 billion, $500 billion, a trillion dollars. And every smart organization at scale
听到4000亿美元、5000亿美元、一万亿美元。以及每个规模化的智能组织
understands that. So they really want to. And I think the space that we want to move forward
明白这一点。所以他们真的很想这么做。我认为我们想要前进的空间
is to get those two bridges a bit closer, and we're doing that. So that's a good point, which is
就是让这两座桥更近一些，我们正在这样做。这是一个很好的观点，那就是
that the key properties that you mentioned are actually not in tension with what institutions
你提到的关键属性实际上与什么机构没有冲突
actively looking for. And if we can better communicate that, it would help. So what do
积极寻找。如果我们能够更好地沟通这一点，将会有所帮助。那怎么办
you have to say for some of the feedback that we've gotten that Ethereum is too principled
对于我们收到的一些反馈，你不得不说以太坊太有原则了
and that it's actually not being pragmatic? I think it ends up being a fantastic filter for
这实际上并不务实？我认为它最终成为一个很棒的过滤器
the types of adoption that we want. So the principles are the things that keep us together
我们想要的收养类型。所以原则是让我们团结在一起的东西
and what we should continue to enhance. So following that tension, the last point
以及我们应该继续加强的方面。因此，在这种紧张之后，最后一点
would be about UX, because a lot of the attempts at improving Ethereum UX has been at the cost of
与用户体验有关，因为许多改进以太坊用户体验的尝试都是以牺牲用户体验为代价的。
some of these principles. So actually for Patrick, this is just a final question for you, which is
其中一些原则。所以实际上对于帕特里克来说，这只是你的最后一个问题，那就是
that when you're in conversation with a lot of these institutions, how much of this progress
当你与很多这样的机构进行对话时，这些进展有多少
about improving UX while still remaining true to our principles is visible to these institutions?
对于这些机构来说，在改进用户体验的同时仍然忠于我们的原则是显而易见的吗？
And where do you think it's going to go from here? I think there's two ways to answer that. So I think
您认为接下来会走向何方？我认为有两种方法可以回答这个问题。所以我认为
first off, a lot of the problems institutions have when they interface with crypto is just the sheer
首先，机构在与加密货币交互时遇到的许多问题只是纯粹的问题
technical difficulty to do so. You know, it's not even about trade-offs and principles. It's just
这样做的技术难度。你知道，这甚至不是权衡和原则的问题。这只是
they just try to download Metamask, they get their hardware wallet, they go and go and save or use
他们只是尝试下载 Metamask，获得硬件钱包，然后去保存或使用
Wallet Connect, and they're just like, boom, it didn't work. So then what they have to use is more
钱包连接，他们就像，繁荣，它不起作用。那么他们必须使用的就是更多
like a custodial bank-like MPC service provider where there's a counterparty. And sometimes they
就像有交易对手的类似托管银行的 MPC 服务提供商。有时他们
like that. They like the idea they can call someone up and be like, oh, I'm logged out, help me.
像那样。他们喜欢这样的想法：他们可以打电话给某人，然后说，哦，我已经注销了，帮帮我吧。
I like that too, yeah. Yeah, people do like that, of course. It's all about counterparty risk.
我也喜欢这样，是的。是的，人们当然喜欢这样。这都是关于交易对手风险的。
But the problem is that if we can't get the software to work, they're forced to be in that
但问题是，如果我们无法让软件运行，他们就被迫这样做
direction and they no longer have a choice. It's not an option. So that's one thing we need to fix
方向，他们不再有选择。这不是一个选择。所以这是我们需要解决的一件事
because otherwise they will rise up and all our goals towards removing counterparties and
因为否则他们就会起来，我们所有的目标都是消除交易对手和
enabling the individual and institution. And by the way, institutions who hold millions of dollars,
为个人和机构提供支持。顺便说一句，持有数百万美元的机构，
if they can reduce counterparty risk or remove it, that's a big win for them.
如果他们能够降低或消除交易对手风险，那对他们来说就是一个巨大的胜利。
Another way to answer, and I was sort of debating about how to answer this here, and I want to
另一种回答方式，我正在争论如何在这里回答这个问题，我想
maybe get a flavor of the audience before I do. So one last time to raise your hands,
也许在我之前先让观众了解一下。所以最后一次举手，
if your job is to deal with like regulations or legal agreements or licenses as part of your job,
如果您的工作是处理类似的法规或法律协议或许可证作为您工作的一部分，
you know, raise your hand if you have to deal with legal agreements on a daily basis.
如果您每天必须处理法律协议，请举手。
Anyone here has to deal with legal agreements. I think some people, I bet they do. Everyone's
这里的任何人都必须处理法律协议。我想有些人，我敢打赌他们是这样的。每个人的
really shy, aren't they? So the reason why do I bring that up? So I think it's really important
真的很害羞，不是吗？那么我为什么要提出这个问题呢？所以我认为这非常重要
for institutions because they understand, you know, regulations. The whole point of a regulation
对于机构来说，因为他们了解法规。法规的全部要点
is to set rules that protect consumers and they have to adhere to these rules.
就是制定保护消费者的规则，消费者必须遵守这些规则。
Legal agreements are about rules of engagement. I send an agreement review and this sets the rules
法律协议是关于参与规则的。我发送协议审核并制定规则
of how we engage. And the license is really to say that I've proved to someone, you know,
我们如何参与。许可证实际上是说我已经向某人证明了，你知道，
a trusted third party, maybe some, you know, authority that I adhere to the regulation
一个值得信赖的第三方，也许是一些我遵守法规的权威机构
and I'm a good actor and I'm doing my best. But in all three scenarios, the issue is that if I break
我是一个好演员，我正在尽我所能。但在所有三种情况下，问题是如果我打破
the rules, it's not detected for a very long time. You know, a user can't detect when a rule is
按照规则，很长一段时间都没有被检测到。您知道，用户无法检测到规则何时生效
broken, neither can an authority. And when it does get detected, you have to spend like months or
破碎了，权威也不能。当它确实被发现时，你必须花费几个月或
even a year, you know, winding back and working out when was the rule broken and what are the
甚至一年，你知道，回过头来看看规则是什么时候被打破的，有什么
consequences of that. And obviously every institution hates that. It's difficult to
这样做的后果。显然每个机构都讨厌这样。很难
detect when rules are broken and then it's hard to do recourse or resolve the dispute.
检测何时违反规则，然后就很难追索或解决争议。
What's really, really nice about blockchains is that they're publicly verifiable and the rules
区块链真正非常好的地方在于它们是可公开验证的并且规则
are enforced in real time. If you say these are the rules of engagement, these are the rules of how
是实时执行的。如果你说这些是参与规则，那么这些就是如何进行的规则
the system works and these are the rules you have to follow. The smart contract code will enforce
系统是有效的，这些是你必须遵守的规则。智能合约代码将强制执行
that for every single transaction in real time. It's, you know, it's not instead of being, you know,
每笔交易都是实时的。它是，你知道，它不是，你知道，
I won't be evil, it's I can't be evil. And when you say that to an institution, they're like,
我不会作恶，而是我不能作恶。当你对某个机构这么说时，他们会说，
boom, light bulb. I get it. That is why this is awesome. And I want to interact with it. And then,
繁荣，灯​​泡。我得到它。这就是为什么这太棒了。我想与它互动。进而，
of course, the UI blows up because like, oh, this is too hard. So we really need to fix the UI
当然，用户界面会崩溃，因为就像，哦，这太难了。所以我们确实需要修复 UI
because it has all the properties that institutions want. And they get it once you explain it in no
因为它具有机构想要的所有属性。一旦你用不解释的方式解释，他们就会明白
manner in their language and you make that comparison. Thank you. And so that concludes the
用他们的语言方式进行比较。谢谢。至此结束
panel for today. Congratulations to the launch of the Ethereum Applications Guild. I think we
今天的小组。祝贺以太坊应用程序协会成立。我想我们
have a bright future ahead and I'll see you next year. Thank you, everyone. Let's take a picture
前途光明，明年再见。谢谢大家。我们来拍张照片吧
before you leave the stage. Camera. Thanks again to everyone for the great discussion.
在你离开舞台之前。相机。再次感谢大家的精彩讨论。
We now arrive at our final panel for this chapter, Ethereum Meets Hardware,
我们现在到达本章的最后一个小组，以太坊遇见硬件，
From Devices to Autonomous Systems. Please welcome our moderator, Leo Lin,
从设备到自治系统。欢迎我们的主持人Leo Lin，
co-founder of Akring, along with our panelists, Ben Zhai, CEO of Robo AI,
Akring 联合创始人，以及我们的小组成员，Robo AI 首席执行官 Ben Zhai，
Wallace Lin, General Manager Hong Kong at Star5, Nijika, Head Product Manager at Liptik Tech,
Wallace Lin，Star5 香港总经理，Nijika，Liptik Tech 首席产品经理，
and Kelly Luo, VP at Face Technology. Please welcome them all. Good afternoon, everyone.
和 Face Technology 副总裁 Kelly Luo。请大家欢迎他们。大家下午好。
Welcome to this panel. Yeah, Ethereum Meets Hardware, From Devices to Autonomous Systems.
欢迎来到这个小组。是的，以太坊遇到了硬件，从设备到自治系统。
So I'm the co-founder of Akring. My name is Leo Lin and the Akring is the global renewable
所以我是 Akring 的联合创始人。我的名字是 Leo Lin，Akring 是全球可再生能源
energy network and we connect the renewable energy sources like the solar panel, the strawberry,
能源网络，我们连接可再生能源，如太阳能电池板、草莓、
and the multi-time energy asset with the on-chain protocol. And we are quite focused on the
以及具有链上协议的多时间能源资产。我们非常关注
IoT and the blockchain, the Web3, the hardware, the interior innovation, and also driving the
物联网和区块链、Web3、硬件、内饰创新，也推动了
initiative of the smart open machine economy. So it's super happy to be here to moderate the session
智能开放机器经济的倡议。所以我非常高兴能够来到这里主持会议
so when people are talking about the Ethereum, so most people think about the finance, the asset,
所以当人们谈论以太坊时，大多数人都会想到金融、资产，
the smart contract, but today's panel we will discuss with a little bit different angle.
智能合约，但今天的小组我们将从稍微不同的角度进行讨论。
So can the Ethereum be part of the coordination layer for the machine, the hardware, the device,
那么以太坊可以成为机器、硬件、设备协调层的一部分吗？
the aging, and the open, the hardware, the system? Because when the hardware has the intelligence
老化、开放、硬件、系统？因为当硬件具备智能时
become the physical AI agent and we believe that gradually they will be the autonomous
成为物理人工智能代理，我们相信它们将逐渐成为自主的
and definitely the device, the hardware will need the identity, the trust, the verification,
当然，设备、硬件将需要身份、信任、验证，
the coordination, and in some cases also the economy interaction. So today we will explore
协调，在某些情况下还有经济互动。那么今天我们将探讨
this with the four different but highly connected examples by our four panelists and they are coming
我们的四位小组成员提供了四个不同但高度相关的例子，他们即将到来
from the industry. It's very important and the RoboEye is a non-statistic company and
来自行业。这非常重要，RoboEye 是一家非统计公司，
offering the RoboCard, the Evoto, and all those are cool, you know, the mobile robotics
提供 RoboCard、Evoto 以及所有这些都很酷的移动机器人
are the solution and Starfy is leading the open source, the RISC-FI, the chipset, the platform,
是解决方案，Starfy 引领开源、RISC-FI、芯片组、平台、
the provider. Last year they were just invited by the Hong Kong IC. Yeah, very cool.
提供者。去年他们刚刚受到香港IC的邀请。是的，非常酷。
And the LipTik is the shining star. Cool. And they offer the AI-based camera and the AI
LipTik 是一颗闪亮的明星。凉爽的。他们提供基于人工智能的相机和人工智能
visual solution. And FaceTech, they are very innovative. The solution provider offers the
视觉解决方案。还有 FaceTech，他们非常有创新精神。解决方案提供商提供
renewable energy and the solar battery, the solution. So let's start today's panel discussion.
可再生能源和太阳能电池，解决方案。那么让我们开始今天的小组讨论吧。
So firstly we let our panelists to have the self-introduction and also share
所以首先我们让我们的小组成员进行自我介绍并分享
what exactly does the hardware and the technology connecting with the easily and also the broader
硬件和技术到底是如何与更便捷、更广泛的连接的？
the ecosystem. Let's start with the Ben from the RoboEye. Thank you, Leo.
生态系统。让我们从 RoboEye 中的 Ben 开始。谢谢你，利奥。
Actually I've been looking forward to this session not only because of the fellow panelists
事实上，我一直期待这次会议不仅是因为小组成员
and our dear friend from Akron, Leo, and a lot of friends sitting in the audience but also I really
还有我们来自阿克伦的亲爱的朋友 Leo，以及坐在观众席上的很多朋友，但我真的
look forward to the next session to Mr. Xiaofeng and Vitalik. The reason I said this is we are a
期待下一场小峰先生和Vitalik的会议。我这么说的原因是我们是一个
public listed company in Nasdaq but based in Dubai because you know you can imagine it took
在纳斯达克上市的公司，但总部设在迪拜，因为你知道你可以想象它花了
a lot of effort to come all the way from Dubai given what's going on over there to come to join
考虑到那里正在发生的事情，我从迪拜千里迢迢来到这里参加
this session. Why we think it's very important because our company RoboEye was listed in
本次会议。为什么我们认为这非常重要，因为我们公司 RoboEye 已在
Nasdaq a few years ago but initially as an EV company as you know 10 years ago that was a really
几年前在纳斯达克上市，但最初作为一家电动汽车公司，正如你所知，十年前那是一家真正的公司
the starting point of the Chinese EV industry. We were quite lucky we started business more
中国电动汽车产业的起点。我们很幸运，我们开始做更多的生意
than 10 years ago and three years ago we went public initially as an EV company and then I
十多年前和三年前，我们最初作为一家电动汽车公司上市，然后我
think over the last couple years the EV industry has been extremely competitive and as a Dubai-based
认为在过去几年中，电动汽车行业的竞争非常激烈，并且作为总部位于迪拜的
hardware company that you know our supply chain our manufacturing cost and technology and so on
硬件公司，你了解我们的供应链，我们的制造成本和技术等等
and so forth we need to find something very different from the traditional hardware manufacturer.
等等我们需要找到一些与传统硬件制造商非常不同的东西。
So luckily over the last couple years the board and the management we looked around to see what's
幸运的是，在过去的几年里，董事会和管理层我们环顾四周，看看有什么
there for the future because UAE as a country has been always focusing on the technology of the future.
未来是因为阿联酋作为一个国家一直关注未来的技术。
So luckily we had a lot of interactions with the companies in blockchain, Hushkey, Hushglobal
幸运的是，我们与区块链、Hushkey、Hushglobal 等公司进行了很多互动
and Akron and over the last 12 months we have you know finally found our future direction
和阿克伦，在过去 12 个月里，我们终于找到了我们未来的方向
and almost our destination, our destiny we call machine economy. That's when we see the potential
几乎我们的目的地，我们的命运，我们称之为机器经济。那是我们看到潜力的时候
that the smart mobility where we came from to connect with the smart machine where we are
我们来自的智能移动与我们所在的智能机器连接
investing like a final panelist but eventually moving to the smart assets that to meet and
像最后的小组成员一样进行投资，但最终转向智能资产，以满足和
connect with the blockchain. So that was a basically the high level visions of the company
与区块链连接。这基本上就是公司的高层愿景
and I'm happy to share more in the next round. Thank you. Hello thank you for having us here.
我很高兴在下一轮中分享更多内容。谢谢。您好，谢谢您邀请我们来到这里。
My name is Wallace, I'm from Star5 Hong Kong. Our company was founded in 2018. It's leading efforts
我叫Wallace，来自香港Star5。我公司成立于2018年，领先的努力
in the RISC-V space in IPs as well as ship designs and more recently actually in also designing and
在 IP 和船舶设计的 RISC-V 领域，最近实际上也在设计和
deploying total solutions around RISC-V. Where I see RISC-V comes into play with Ethereum as well
围绕 RISC-V 部署整体解决方案。我看到 RISC-V 也与以太坊一起发挥作用
as the web-free ecosystem is really around free areas. I think one is about enhanced execution
因为无网络生态系统实际上是围绕自由区域的。我认为其中之一是关于增强执行力
efficiency you know how our open architecture actually enables that. The other one is actually
效率您知道我们的开放式架构实际上是如何实现这一点的。另一位其实是
also about how we can actually support the zero knowledge proving with our technology and last
还关于我们如何能够用我们的技术和最后的方法来实际支持零知识证明
but not least you know also is essentially how we can enable you know a lot of the you know off-chain
但最重要的是，你知道本质上也是我们如何让你知道很多你知道的链下信息
activities via our technology as well. So our company is relatively new to this space but we're
也通过我们的技术进行活动。所以我们公司在这个领域相对较新，但我们
definitely very excited about what's happening in this space and definitely hope that the hard
对这个领域正在发生的事情绝对感到非常兴奋，并且绝对希望困难
work can play a key role in integrating with the software solutions. Yeah thank you. Hello guys,
工作可以在与软件解决方案的集成中发挥关键作用。是的，谢谢。大家好，
it's so good to be here. I am Nijika, I'm from the Leap2Tech and I am working on the imaging
很高兴来到这里。我是 Nijika，来自 Leap2Tech，从事成像工作
technology and for recent years we see that the imaging devices like GoPros doesn't like
技术，近年来我们发现像 GoPros 这样的成像设备不喜欢
like the cameras you just take the photos but only the it's not only for the capture moment
就像相机一样，你只是拍照，但不仅仅是为了捕捉瞬间
but also they help the records and understand people's life and when you in the past and
而且它们还有助于记录和了解人们的生活以及当你过去和
the people take the photos and you have to recognize this kind of thing and you should
人们拍照，你必须认识到这种事情，你应该
take the person and now the cameras come to continuous recording
带走这个人，现在摄像机开始连续记录
and it's not only for the creative materials anymore it is also data for the visual memory
它不再只是创意材料，也是视觉记忆的数据
library. The device records automatically and then model understands, organizes, indexes
图书馆。设备自动记录，模型理解、组织、索引
and records that data, highlights rows, reminders, meeting notes and recommendations.
并记录数据、突出显示行、提醒、会议记录和建议。
Devices are becoming more and more connected in Webbrie and this is why we are here
Webbrie 中的设备互联程度越来越高，这就是我们来到这里的原因
to build a corner in the layer to make these cameras, glasses,
在图层中建立一个角落来制作这些相机、眼镜、
AI rings, like phones, like vacuums, cars, chips, we are building a family that
AI戒指，就像手机，就像吸尘器、汽车、芯片，我们正在建立一个家庭
all the computers work in the same works in the open network so thanks.
所有计算机在开放网络中都以相同的方式工作，所以谢谢。
Thank you Leo. Hello everyone. I'm from Shenzhen Face Technology, a national high tech enterprise
谢谢你利奥。大家好。我来自国家高新技术企业深圳市菲斯科技
focusing on IoT and new energy. We develop a four core household new energy system which is
专注于物联网和新能源。我们研发的四核心家用新能源系统
affordable, manageable and operational and sustainable built on our self-developed hardware.
经济实惠、可管理、可运营且可持续，建立在我们自主开发的硬件之上。
We mainly serve energy poor households in Africa, Asia and Latin America providing stable and clean
我们主要为非洲、亚洲和拉丁美洲的能源贫困家庭提供稳定和清洁的服务
distributed residential power solutions. We have a full chain research and development capabilities
分布式住宅电力解决方案。我们拥有全链条研发能力
with core products including household energy storage, portable power stations and cloud
核心产品包括家用储能、便携式电站、云
management platform. Our products are reliable and easy to deploy and suitable for large-scale
管理平台。我们的产品可靠且易于部署，适合大规模
applications overseas. On how we interrogate our products in with Web3, first we connect
海外申请。关于我们如何使用 Web3 询问我们的产品，首先我们连接
our hardware with blockchain. All devices can generate real and traceable energy carbon data
我们的硬件与区块链。所有设备均可生成真实、可追溯的能源碳数据
which is uploaded on chain and to clarify asset ownership. Second, we use Web3 to acculate
上传到链上并明确资产所有权。二、我们使用Web3来累加